(お登勢)ｱﾝﾀが
友達 連れてくるなんてねぇ｡
I never would have expected
you to bring friends.
珍しいこともあるもんだよ｡
Now there's a rare sight.
あたしゃ てっきり
まだ 一匹で➡
I figured you were still running
around on your own.
つっぱってるもんだと
思ってたよ｡
まったく… 敵を作るのばかり
うまくなっちまって｡
Honestly, you've got a real
knack for making enemies.
ねぇ ｱﾝﾀら｡
Hey, guys.
(お登勢)ｺｲﾂはね 人が言うほど
悪いﾔﾂじゃないんだ｡
This fella isn't as bad as people say.
他の連中より ちょいと
不器用なだけなのさ｡
He's just a bit more awkward than most.
(ﾎｳｲﾁ)ちっ うるせえﾊﾞﾊﾞｱだ｡
Bah, mouthy old hag.
おい 行くぞ｡ ﾃﾒｴら｡
(銀時)え… ちょ… 待っ｡
Hey, let's get going.
Huh? Wait, what...
もう 十分食ったろ｡
Haven't you had enough to eat?
You're already leaving?
もう行くのかい？
相変わらず つれないﾔﾂだねぇ｡
I see that you're as unfriendly as ever.
How many years will pass
before I see you again?
次会えるのは 何年後だい？
気をつけんだよ｡
ﾀﾏ抜かれないように｡
Be careful.
Don't get your balls taken.
If they catch you, you'll never
be able to return to this town.
(お登勢)連中に捕まったら
この街には➡
二度と戻ってこれないよ｡
(ﾎｳｲﾁ)ﾌﾝ｡
ちょいとｱﾝﾀ｡
You there.
Look after him for me.
ｱｲﾂのこと よろしく頼んだよ｡
ﾆｬｰｵ｡
["Freedom means to live true
to yourself, not without law!"]
Sorry about the lack of manners
around this place.
(勝男)すんまへんな｡
行儀の悪いﾔﾂばかりで｡
ﾎﾝﾏ どいつもこいつも
性悪そうなﾂﾗしくさってからに｡
Seriously, every one of them looks
ready to bite your head off.
やっぱり 飼うなら
猫やのうて 犬でんな｡
Dogs make much better pets than cats.
(勝男)犬は 主人に忠実やし➡
Dogs are loyal to their masters and
those eyes just make you want to pet them,
あの目 見とったらなんや
手ぇ差し伸べたくなりまっけど｡
ｺｲﾂらときたら
主人もなんも 関係あらへん｡
but these freaks don't give a
damn about their masters.
ｴｻさえもらえば
誰にでもとびつく｡
They'll follow anyone if
they get food out of it.
腹ん中で
何考えてんのか わからん｡
Nobody can tell what they're scheming.
ﾎﾝﾏ 怖い生き物でっせ｡
Scary creatures, for real.
勝男殿｡
Mr. Katsuo...
それは 我々に向けての言葉と
とってもよろしいのでしょうか？
Am I to interpret your words
as slander against us?
おっと｡ こら すんまへん｡
他意はありまへん｡
Whoops, sorry about that.
No ill intentions.
ｳﾁのﾒﾙちゃんが いちばん
かわいいっちゅう話でんがな｡
I was talking about how my Mel-chan
is the cutest in the world.
どうやら この街の猫たちは➡
It appears that the cats in this town have
more spirit than your average stray.
そこいらの野良より
ひときわ ｲｷがいいようだ｡
実に いい素材です｡
Excellent specimens.
これなら 言い値の２割
上乗せしてもいい｡
I'm willing to pay double your price.
Man, you for real?
(勝男)ﾎﾝﾏでっか？
こんなんでよければ➡
If this is what you want, I can run
out and catch you a buttload.
まだまだ ｼﾞｬﾝｼﾞｬﾝ
捕まえてきまっせ｡
ｺｲﾂら ただの野良やさかい｡
They're just strays.
いなくなって
喜ぶﾔﾂはおっても➡
The people will rejoice if they're gone.
Nobody will complain.
騒ぎたてるﾔﾂは
誰もおらんのです｡
Well, I doubt that they realize we're
cutting deals behind closed doors.
ま 裏でこんな商いが
行われてんのは➡
知りもしないでしょうが｡
黒猫は あるところでは➡
In some places, black cats are
considered to be bad luck,
不吉を招くものとして
忌み嫌われていますが➡
あるところでは
幸福を招くものとされています｡
yet in other places, they are
considered to be good luck.
猫とは ２つの顔を
持っている生き物なんです｡
Cats are creatures with two sides.
あなたたちにとっては
ただのｼﾞｬﾏ者かもしれない｡
You people may consider
them nuisances,
だが 我々にとっては➡
but we consider them messiahs
who will save our planet.
彼らは 星を救うﾒｼｱ
たりえるのです｡
我々は
派手に動くことはできません｡
We cannot take action which will
draw attention to us.
これからも 我が星のために
ご協力お願いできますか？
Can we count on your cooperation
in assisting our planet?
Bro, how did negotiations go?
兄貴 どうでした？
交渉のほうは｡
(勝男)何がﾒｼｱや｡
ﾎﾝﾏ 怖い生き物やで｡
Messiahs, my ass.
Cats are scary creatures, for real.
猫っちゅうんは｡
Hey, you hear about the
ball removal mess?
おい 聞いたかよ｡
例のﾀﾏ狩りの話｡
ｷﾝﾀﾏ抜かれたら➡
Originally, I heard you'd be released
after they took your balls,
それでまた ここに戻ってこれる
みたいな話だったが｡
どうも 戻ってきてねえらしいぜ
捕まった連中｡
but nobody's come back.
ﾀﾏどころか 魂抜かれちまう
なんてｳﾜｻも流れてるぜ｡
There's a rumor going around
that they even take your soul.
そういや 最近
ﾎｳｲﾁの野郎も見ねえな｡ まさか｡
Oh, yeah. I haven't seen
Hoichi around lately...
He couldn't have...
Of course not.
んなわけねえだろ｡
ﾎｳｲﾁなら またｱｲﾂとお出かけよ｡
Hoichi's out with that guy again.
The newbie?
新入りのｱｲﾂか｡
Fool! Conceal your presence!
ﾊﾞｶ野郎 気配を消せ｡
Hey, isn't this bad?
おい まずくねえか？
あのｷﾞﾝって野郎も➡
That Gin fella was pretty strong.
相当 腕の立つ野郎だったぜ｡
If he joins up with Hoichi,
we'll be nothing.
あれとﾎｳｲﾁと組まれちゃ➡
いよいよ
ｵﾚたちの立つ瀬がなくなる｡
捕まっちまえばいいのに｡
If only he would get caught.
ｱｲﾂさえ いなくなりゃ
ｵﾚたちゃ 自由になるじゃねえか｡
Once he's gone, we'll be free, right?
しかたねえ｡ 今日はここまでだ｡
Guess that's it. We'll call it a day.
ったく 何度やっても
狩りがうまくならねえ野郎だ｡
Man, you still can't learn to
hunt after all these tries.
んなこっちゃ
ここじゃ生きていけねえぜ｡
You're not gonna be able
to survive in this place.
かっ… 狩りなんざ➡
I-I don't want to learn how to hunt!
うまくなんかなりたくねえ
つってんだよ！
ｽｽﾞﾒなんて あんな愛らしいもん
食えるわけねえだろ！
How am I supposed to eat
a cute little sparrow?!
ｵﾚは ﾃﾒｴとは育ちが違うんだよ！
I wasn't raised the way you were!
人間なの！ 何度言ったら
わかるんだ｡ ﾀｺ助！
I'm human!
How many times do I have
to tell you this, dimwit?!
おい！ ｵﾒｴらも
何とか言ってやれ！
Hey! You guys should pitch in!
(近藤)あ～んぐ｡
(桂)ﾎｳｲﾁ殿 塩がいいですか？
ﾀﾚがいいですか？
Master Hoichi, do you
prefer salt? Or sauce?
銀時 お前はどうする？
あっ ｵﾚ塩で…｡
Gintoki, what about you?
Oh, I'll have salt...
Wait! You guys adapt too fast!
って お前ら 順応早すぎだろっ！
(ﾎｳｲﾁ)どうやら ｺｲﾂらのほうが
野良の才能はあるようだな｡
It appears that they have
what it takes to be strays.
たき火たく 野良猫が
どこの世界にいんだよ！
What kind of stray cat would build a fire?!
Hey, Odd Jobs! Come join us!
(近藤)おい万事屋 お前もこいよ！
一緒に ｷｬﾝﾌﾟﾌｧｲｱ- 囲もうぜ｡
We can sit around the campfire!
お前らが燃えて灰になれ！
You people can burn into ashes!
あぁ 腹減って眠れねえ｡
Ah, I'm so hungry I can't sleep.
いったい いつまで続くんだ
この生活…｡
How long am I going to
have to live like this?
いつになったら
ｵﾚは 元に戻れるんだ｡
When will I turn back to normal?
新八 神楽… 何してっかな…｡
Shinpachi... Kagura...
Wonder how they're doing?
ったく
あきらめの悪い野郎だな｡
Man, you don't know when to give up.
ｷﾞﾝ…
ﾃﾒｴらは もう人間には戻れねえよ｡
Gin, you can no longer go
back to being human.
ｹｯ… ｵﾚの戯言なんざ➡
Hah, I figured you weren't
listening to my babbling.
聞き流してるもんだと
思ってたがな｡
信じてんのかよ｡
あんなｱﾎみたいな話｡
You believe my ridiculous story?
ﾌﾝ 信じてなきゃ
どうして このｵﾚが➡
Why would I waste my time on
you if I didn't believe you?
ﾃﾒｴらなんざ 相手にするってんだ｡
あっ？
Huh?
ったく 同じ道行く先人として➡
I wanted to give you advice as someone
who's been down this path,
ｱﾄﾞﾊﾞｲｽをくれてやろうと思ったら
こうも鈍いﾔﾂだったとはな｡
but I didn't expect you to
be so slow in the head.
お… お前まさか…｡
D-Don't tell me...
ようやく気づいたかよ｡
そんな…｡
You finally noticed?
No way...
お前… ﾄﾞﾗえも…｡
You're Doraemo-
[Note: Doreamon, the robotic cat from the future.]
No!
(ﾎｳｲﾁ)違う～！ 全然違う！
Not even close!
なんで 今の話の流れで
ﾄﾞﾗえもんが出てきやがんだ！
How could you get Doraemon
from what I just said?!
Well, I figured you meant that
you're a cat from the future.
いや～ 未来猫的な意味で
先人かと…｡
耳も ﾈｽﾞﾐにかじられちゃって
ないのかと…｡
And perhaps your ears had
been bitten off by mice.
When did I ever say that
I had been bitten by mice?!
誰が ﾈｽﾞﾐにかじられたつったよ｡
誰が 四次元ﾎﾟｹｯﾄ持ってる
っつったよ！
When did I ever say that I had
a four-dimensional pocket?!
え～ じゃあ ﾄﾞﾗえもん
じゃなかったら何なんだよ？
Huh? So if you aren't Doraemon,
then what?
え？ ひょっとして…
お前！ パ パ… ﾊﾟｰﾆｬﾝ!?
Could it be that you're Pa-Pa-
Pa-meow?!
It's Pa-man!
[Note: Pa-man, boy superhero manga by the creator of Doraemon.]
ﾊﾟｰﾏﾝだろ！ 何 勝手に
微妙にｱﾚﾝｼﾞ加えてんだ！
Don't change it slightly!
Not even close!
いねえよ！ ｷﾞﾘｷﾞﾘﾁﾝﾊﾟﾝｼﾞｰまでだよ
２号のほうの！
Okay, maybe the chimpanzee, Pa-man 2!
お… おい ｳｿだろ｡
じゃあ お前…｡
H-Hey, you've gotta be kidding.
Then you...
なんで…
なんで こんな所に ﾌﾘｰｻﾞ様が！
Why?
Why is Lord Frieza here?!
[Note: Frieza is a famous villain
from the manga Dragon Ball.]
My forehead's the only
thing that's even close!
おでこだけだろ！
わからねえのか？
Can't you tell...?
ｵﾚも お前らと同じ 元人間だよ｡
I used to be a human,
same as you guys.
Huh? Huh?!
え… えぇ～!?
お… お前
ﾌﾘｰｻﾞ様 最終形態じゃないの!?
Y-You aren't the final
form of Lord Frieza?!
That's what you're surprised about?!
驚くとこ そこ!?
Hold on!
ちょっと待て！
お前 ここで もう何年も➡
You've been the boss cat around
here for many years, right?
ﾎﾞｽ猫 やってんだよな？ 何年？
How many years?
いったい何年 猫のまんまなんだ？
How many years have you been a cat?
猫になったのは 13年前だ｡
I turned into a cat thirteen years ago.
だから言ったのさ｡
もう 元には戻れねえと｡
So like I said, you can no longer go back.
まぁ ｵﾚとお前らとじゃ➡
Well, your curse is probably
different from mine.
背負った呪いの重さも
違うんだろうが…｡
もう あきらめてんのか？
人間に戻るのを…｡
You've already given up on
turning back into a human?
ｺｲﾂは ｵﾚの咎だ｡
逃げるわけにはいかねえんだ｡
This is my penance.
I can't run away.
It is my burden to bear.
背負っていかなきゃならねえんだ｡
ｵﾚはな 猫になる前も
ﾛｸでもねえﾔﾂだったんだ｡
I was a lousy bastard even before
I became a cat.
今と何にも変わらねえ｡
No different from what I am now.
A despicable man who twisted arms and
used force to get what he wanted.
力で何でもねじ伏せる
忌み嫌われる存在だった｡
違うのは
てっぺんなんかには程遠い➡
The only difference was that I was a mere
yakuza at the bottom of the chain.
ﾔｸｻﾞに飼われた
ただの ﾁﾝﾋﾟﾗだってことぐらいだ｡
上の命令となりゃ
誰彼かまわず 殺りにいった｡
I killed anyone and everyone if ordered.
I took more human lives than
I could possibly count.
数えきれねえ程の
人間の命を この手で奪った｡
ｵﾚは 悪くねえ｡
It wasn't my fault.
I was a hired gun,
so I didn't have a choice.
飼われてるんだから
しかたねえ｡
ｴｻに ありつくためには
I had to make a living.
I shifted all the blame to my employer.
都合の悪いことは
全部 飼い主のせいにした｡
頭空っぽにして
従順に働き続けた…｡
Emptied my mind of thought and
focused on working obediently.
そんなときだ｡
But one day...
I spotted a stray, brilliantly free, so unlike
how I was bound to my employer.
飼い主に縛られ
がんじがらめになっている➡
ｵﾚとは違う 自由気ままに生きる
一匹の野良が➡
ひどく輝いて見えた｡
いつの間にか ﾔﾂにｴｻやんのが
ｵﾚの日課になってたよ｡
The next thing I knew, I was
feeding him every day.
殺伐とした日々の中で➡
My only freedom during those brutal days
came when I was playing with him.
ﾔﾂと たわむれているときだけ
ｵﾚは自由になれた｡
それからだ｡
ｵﾚが 人を斬れなくなったのは…｡
After that, I could no longer kill people.
いくら 人 斬っても
感じることのなかった➡
After cutting down so many people
without feeling a thing,
命の重みってやつを➡
自分で触れた
ほんの小さな命によって➡
my encounter with this small creature
was what taught me the value of life.
ｵﾚは 初めて知ったのさ｡
もう 人は斬らない｡
I would no longer kill.
勝手に ﾔﾂと約束した｡
That was the promise I made him.
それでも 飼い主から 下知が下る｡
But my employer was
still giving me orders.
特攻に近い仕事だった｡
A suicide mission for all
intents and purposes.
ｵﾚが役に立たなくなっているのを
気づいていたんだろう｡
He must have noticed that
I had outlived my usefulness.
死ぬつもりだった｡
I was prepared to die.
また命を奪うくらいなら
死んだほうがいい｡
I would rather die than take another life.
そう思った｡
That's how I felt.
気がつくと
周りは 血の海になってた｡
The next thing I knew, I was
surrounded by a sea of blood.
血の海の中に ｵﾚらしき人間が
沈んでるのが見えた｡
I could see a human that resembled
me within that sea of blood.
I broke my promise and
ended up in this form.
ｵﾚは 約束 破って
こんな姿になったのさ｡
だが ﾔﾂは 体 与えてまで
ｵﾚを生き長らえさせた｡
Yet he gave me his body
to help me survive.
だから決めたんだ｡ ｵﾚは 今まで➡
So I made up my mind.
Until that point, I had taken away many
things that could never be replaced.
かけがえのねえものを
奪い続けてきた｡
だが この体は…
ﾔﾂからもらった この体は➡
But I would use this body,
the precious body he gave me,
かけがえのないもんを
守るために使う｡
to protect those things that
can never be replaced.
耳をちぎられようが
嫌われようが 一匹になろうが➡
My ears may end up tattered, I may be
universally hated, I may end alone,
この体が朽ちるまで守りとおす｡
but I will protect those things
until this body dies.
As I thought.
やはりな｡ あの洗礼と呼ばれる
新人いびりも➡
Your practice of harassing newbies
was to protect those cats.
猫を守るためであろう｡
この生存競争が激しい かぶき町を
生き抜く力が あるかどうか｡
You attacked them so you could
personally test to see if
they have what it takes to survive
in this brutal Kabukicho.
その身をもって試し
ふるいにかけていたんだな｡
無用な命が散らぬように｡
力任せの恐怖政治は➡
To avoid needless loss of life...
You ruled through might and fear
to prevent any foolish action,
野良どもの勝手な動きを抑え➡
人間との軋轢を
生まぬためのもの｡
by the strays,
that would agitate humans.
この町の性悪猫どもには➡
Fear was the only way to control the
foul-tempered cats in this town.
恐怖という概念以外
抑止力となりえん｡
If you're able to understand
that much, you'll be fine.
そこまでわかってれば 上出来だ｡
もう ﾃﾒｴらに教えることはねえ｡
I have nothing more to teach you.
I leave the rest to you.
あとのことは任せたぜ｡
かぶき町のﾎﾞｽ猫は
今から ﾃﾒｴらだ！
From now on, you lot are
the bosses of Kabukicho.
あ～っ！
何 勝手なこと言ってんだ！
Huh?!
Don't decide that on your own!
そんなもん なるわけねえだろ！
We can't possibly do that!
そうだ！ ﾎﾞｽ猫はﾑﾘだ！
ﾎﾞｽｺﾞﾘﾗと改めてください！
Yeah! I can't be a boss cat!
Please change that to a boss gorilla!
そういう問題ではなかろう！
That isn't the issue here!
ﾃﾒｴらなら 大丈夫だ｡
You guys should be fine.
ｵﾚは 年いっちまって
もう あの荒くれ者どもを➡
I'm too old to hold those ruffians back.
抑え込むのは ﾑﾘだ｡
ﾀﾏ狩りが施行されるまでに➡
Our relationship with humans deteriorated to
the point where neutering came into practice
人間との関係が悪化したのは
ｵﾚの支配力不足さ｡
because I wasn't able to control them.
何を言われるか！
己の身を顧みず 猫を守ってきた➡
What are you saying?!
I'm sure that the cats will have a
change of heart when they learn
貴殿の心意気を知れば きっと
猫たちも 心を改めようて！
how you've sacrificed yourself
to protect them!
この街のﾎﾞｽ猫は
ﾎｳｲﾁ殿をおいて 他にはおらん！
You are the only one who can
serve as boss cat in this town!
ｵﾚは 本来
ﾎﾞｽ猫なんぞの器じゃねえ｡
I was never boss cat material.
But there's still something
this old body can do.
だが こんな老体でも まだ
やれることは残ってんだろう｡
Don't tell me...
ﾃﾒｴ まさか
捕まった連中を！
You're going to save the ones
who've been caught?!
Hoichi, you seem to be having
fun with your new friends.
ﾎｳｲﾁよ 友達ができて
ずいぶんと楽しそうじゃねえか｡
遊ぶんなら
ｵﾚたちも まぜてくれよ｡
Let us join in on the fun.
(猫たち)ﾍﾍﾍ…｡
ﾃﾒｴら
こりゃ いったい 何のつもりだ？
Bastards, what's the meaning of this?
ﾍﾍﾍ… ﾎｳｲﾁよ
よくも今まで さんざん偉そうに➡
Hoichi, you've done a fine job of
running roughshod all over us.
ｵﾚたち
踏み潰してくれたよなぁ おい！
だが それも 今日で終わりだ！
But that ends today!
ｽﾞﾀﾎﾞﾛにして 町内会の連中に
首 差し出してやらあ｡
We'll beat you up and turn
you into the neighborhood association.
この街にゃ もうﾎﾞｽはいらねえ｡
This town doesn't need a boss.
ｵﾚたちゃ 自由に生きるんだ！
We're gonna live free!
An uprising?
下克上か！
やめろ！
Enough!
ｷｻﾏら ﾎｳｲﾁ殿が
今まで どんな気持で お前らを！
Do you fools have any idea
how Master Hoichi has...
しゃらくせえ！
全員まとめて たたんじまいな!!
Zip it!
Beat the crap out of them all!
ﾎﾞｽ猫候補は
一人たりとも逃がすんじゃねえ!!
Don't let a single potential
boss cat get away!
逃げろ｡
Run for it.
あとのことは頼んだぜ｡
I'm leaving the rest to you.
ﾎｳｲﾁ!!
Hoichi!
手間が省けたぜ｡
Saves me the trouble.
I was on my way to see the dumb faces
on the cats who've been caught.
ちょうど
町内会に捕まった連中の➡
ﾏﾇｹﾂﾞﾗ 拝みにいこうと
思ってたところよ｡
Now, show me the way.
さぁ 案内してもらおうか｡
What?! He's completely ignoring us!
な… まったく相手にされてねえ！
な…
何で 抵抗しやがらねえんだ ｱｲﾂ｡
Wh-Why doesn't he fight back?!
D-Don't be scared! Flatten him!
ひ… ひるむな！
押し潰しちまえ!!
ｸｯ！
待て 銀時！
Wait, Gintoki!
ｳﾋｬﾋｬﾋｬﾋｬ！
A fine haul!
大漁じゃ～!!
なんや知らんけど
ごっついことになってるやんけ！
Not sure what's going on,
but we're in luck!
まとめて いてもうたれや!!
Got them all in one go!
しまった～!!
Shoot!
We made too much noise and
the humans noticed us!
派手に動きすぎて
人間どもに感づかれた！
What are you doing?!
Get the heck out of here!
なにしてやがんだ！
さっさと逃げやがれ!!
ﾎｳｲﾁ～!!
Hoichi!
The Gutter Rat Gang is apparently behind the
project to capture Kabukicho strays.
(新八)今回の
かぶき町野良猫捕獲計画は➡
裏で 溝鼠組が動いています｡
彼らは 町内会の人々に➡
They told the townspeople that they were neutering
the cats to prevent an infestation,
野良猫の繁殖を防ぐために
去勢を施すという名目で➡
それを捕獲させて➡
when they were actually selling them
off to Planet Catnip's embassy.
木天蓼星大使館に
売り飛ばしていたんです｡
And none of the cats they've
captured have returned.
そして 彼らに捕まった猫たちは➡
一匹たりとも
ここには戻ってきていない｡
やっぱりね｡
Thought so.
どうも おかしいと思ったんだよ｡
I knew that something was up.
昨日の晩も
大捕り物が あったらしくてね｡
I heard that they were on
the hunt again last night.
また ずいぶんと
野良猫が捕まっちまったらしいよ｡
A large number of strays
were caught.
すっかり
ｷﾚｲになっちまったね この街も｡
This town's looking pretty clean now.
お登勢さん…｡
Otose-san, we assisted with the project
to reduce the number of bad cats
ﾎﾞｸら
悪さをする猫が 少しでも減って➡
人も猫も
住みよい街になるようにって➡
so humans and cats would have
an easier time living in this town.
あの計画に協力してきました｡
でも こんなの…｡
But this is...
野良猫一匹いない こんな街…｡
A town without a single stray cat...
ﾎﾞｸは ｷﾚｲだなんて思いません｡
I wouldn't call this clean.
Let's crash 'em!
(神楽)乗り込むｱﾙ！
大使館 乗り込んで➡
Crash the embassy and save the strays!
野良猫たちを助けてくるね！
もしかしたら 銀ちゃんも➡
And Gin-chan might have been
caught up in their conspiracy!
ﾔﾂらの陰謀に
巻き込まれてるのかもしれないね｡
およしよ｡
Forget it.
相手は大使館｡
下手に 手ぇ出したら➡
We're dealing with an embassy here.
One wrong move and you
won't be getting off lightly.
ﾀﾀﾞじゃすまないよ｡
でも！
But!
There's no need to worry.
心配いらないよ｡
You think this is enough to
get rid of the strays
この街で生きてきた野良たちが
こんなもんで➡
根絶やしになっちまうような
連中だと思ってるのかい？
who've managed to
survive in this town?
ﾔﾎﾞなﾏﾈは しちゃいけないよ｡
Don't do anything foolish.
こっからは ﾔﾂらの領分さ｡
This is their territory.
Cats have their own sense of honor.
猫には猫の
仁義ってもんがあんのさ｡
引き返すなら 今のうちだぜ｡
We can still turn back.
こんなﾏﾈしても
この体が 元に戻るわけじゃねえ｡
This won't help us return
to our original bodies.
死ぬかもしれねえ｡ 猫のまんま…｡
We might die.
As cats.
言っただろう？ ﾎｳｲﾁが｡
Didn't you hear Hoichi?
I'm leaving the rest to you.
あとのことは頼んだぜ｡
ｵﾚたち全員いっちまったら➡
If we're all taken out,
who's going to replace Hoichi?
誰が ﾎｳｲﾁの跡を継ぐんだ？
ｵﾚは このとおりｺﾞﾘﾗだ｡
I'm a gorilla, as you can see.
I could never be a boss cat.
ﾎﾞｽ猫なんぞ ﾊﾅからなれん｡
故に 約束を守るいわれもねえ｡
So I have no obligation
to keep that promise.
My apologies to Master Hoichi,
ﾎｳｲﾁ殿には悪いが
ｵﾚも 猫のまま生きるつもりも➡
but I have no intention of living
as a cat or dying as a cat.
猫のまま 死ぬつもりもない｡
侍として生き 侍として死ぬ｡
I will live as a samurai,
and die as a samurai.
猫だろうとｺﾞﾘﾗだろうと
関係ない｡
It doesn't matter if we're cat or gorilla.
友がために戦う｡ それが侍だ｡
We fight for our friends.
That is the samurai way.
そうかい｡
Is that so?
ﾎｳｲﾁ… かぶき町野良王の座➡
Hoichi, as of today, we'll take over your
title as the king of Kabukicho strays.
今日かぎり もらい受ける！
We'll stake everything we have
to protect the things
ﾃﾒｴが今まで すべてをかけて
守ってきたものは➡
you've staked everything to protect.
ｵﾚたちが
すべてをかけて 守りとおす｡
かぶき町ﾎﾞｽ猫連合！ 参る!!
The Kabukicho Boss Cat Alliance!
On the scene!
落とし穴にかかってたらしくて｡
They were caught in a pitfall.
どうやって逃げ出したかねえ｡
I wonder how they escaped.
And why is there a gorilla?
つうか なんで
ｺﾞﾘﾗがいるんだ？
Did we ever catch a gorilla?
ｺﾞﾘﾗなんか捕まえたっけ？
A-All according to plan.
作戦どおりだな｡
そうだな｡
Right...
これで 敵の懐に
入ることに成功した｡
We've successfully infiltrated
the enemy base...
Y-Yeah... Just as planned...
だ だよね！ 作戦どおりだよね｡
So what do we do now?
で これからどうする？
Help!
助けてくれ！ ｵﾚ ｺﾞﾘﾗだから！
I'm a gorilla! Not a cat!
猫じゃないから 関係ね～じゃん！
This has nothing to do with me!
ﾔﾀﾞ！ こんなﾊﾞｶたちと一緒に
死ぬのはｲﾔだ～！
No!
I don't want to die with these fools!
静かにしろ！
ﾃﾒｴ 散々かっこつけといて➡
Keep it down!
After all that big talk,
you breakdown eight scenes later?!
よくも たった８ｶｯﾄで
鞍替えできるよな!?
恥ずかしくねえのか ｺﾞﾘﾗ！
Aren't you ashamed of yourself, gorilla?!
We should all be ashamed after talking
big and walking into that pitfall!
かっこつけて
落とし穴に落ちた時点で➡
全員恥ずかしいんだよ！
なにが？
Why's that? I'm not ashamed at all!
全然恥ずかしくねえけど!?
作戦どおりだし｡
It was all according to plan!
全然 焦ってねえし｡
I'm not worried at all!
仲間割れをしている場合か｡
This isn't the time to fight
amongst ourselves.
早く ここから脱出せねば➡
We must escape at once,
or we're done for,
let alone save Master Hoichi.
ﾎｳｲﾁ殿を救う前に
ｵﾚたちが やられるぞ｡
Look at his belt.
ﾔﾂの腰を見ろ｡
We must grab those keys.
あの鍵を何とか奪うんだ｡
いいか 猫は頭さえ檻から出せば➡
Listen up.
Once a cat squeezes his head
through the bars, he's free.
あとは どうにかなる｡
Zura, you should have a chance
with that tiny brain of yours.
ﾂﾞﾗ ﾃﾒｴの矮小な脳しか
入ってない頭なら➡
いけるはずだ｡
最悪 破裂しても誰も困らねえ｡
Fortunately, nobody will care
if you crack anything.
I will!
ｵﾚが困るわ！
いいから早く行け｡
Just get going. We have no time.
時間ねえんだっつうの｡
おい！
Hey! I'm saying that it's impossible!
ﾑﾘだと言ってるだろ｡
I said to get going!
いいから行けっつってんだろ！
He's out! His body's out!
出た！ 体は出たぞ!!
おい！
Hey! What am I supposed to do now?!
しかし これから
どうすればいいんだ？
首が絞まる！
足を止めたら窒息する！
My neck is stuck tight!
I'll suffocate if my legs fall behind!
ﾃﾞｯｹｴ声出すんじゃねえ！
感づかれるだろ｡
Keep it down! They'll notice!
あとは 頭出すだけだ
踏ん張れ！ ﾎﾗ!!
You just need to get your head out!
Push harder! Come on!
Easy for you to say!
そんなこと言ったって！
あれ？ 何か引っかかったか？
Huh? Is something stuck?
My tail! My tail is caught in
the automatic door!
ｼｯﾎﾟ！ ｼｯﾎﾟ 自動ﾄﾞｱに挟まった！
That's weird. It won't move.
おかしいな 動かないな｡
死ぬ～ 首がとれる!!
Dying!
My head's gonna come off!
出せ～！ さっさと出せ！
生き残るには➡
Out! Get out!
You have to get that head out if you want
to survive! There's no other way!
頭 出すしかねえんだよ！
やるしかねえんだ!!
I'm dying!
死ぬ～！ 頭出す前に
ｷｻﾏらに殺される!!
You're going to kill me before
my head ever pops out!
Pretend like you're the
Tom in Tom and Jerry!
ﾄﾑとｼﾞｪﾘｰの
ﾄﾑになったつもりになれ！
You can do it!
お前ならいける！
ﾄﾑにも追いつける!!
You can match Tom!
Flatten yourself and slip on through!
ﾑﾆｭｰﾝなってｽﾎﾟｰﾝと抜けるはずだ｡
H-He's free!
抜けた でかしたﾂﾞﾗ！
Well done, Zura!
Grab the key and open us up!
早く鍵 奪って ここ開けろ｡
You okay? Still got your tail?
大丈夫か ｼｯﾎﾟ抜けてねえか｡
Yeah, my tail is fine.
あぁ ｵﾚのは大丈夫だ｡
Why is my tail out?!
何でｵﾚのｼｯﾎﾟが抜けてんだ！
Why mine instead of yours?!
何で お前のじゃなくてｵﾚのだ！
Sorry, I grabbed it when I was in pain.
すまん
苦し紛れに つかんでしまった｡
Sorry, my ass!
すまんじゃあねえだろ！
なんで わざわざ➡
Why did you have to pull my tail out?!
ｵﾚのｼｯﾎﾟ抜き去っていかなきゃ
ならねえんだ！
What?! When did you...
お前 いつのまに!?
Hey! Don't use my tail like that!
おい！ 人のｼｯﾎﾟ
何に使ってんだ！
Now's our chance. Get out.
今のうちだ 早く出ろ｡
Why are you using it like a beam saber?!
何でﾋﾞｰﾑｻｰﾍﾞﾙ風？
どうなってるんだ それ！
What's going on with that thing?!
つうか 鍵
まったく必要ねえじゃねえか！
And we didn't even need the key!
返せ！ これはｵﾚが使う｡
Give that back!
I'll use it!
素材が逃げ出してるぞ！
捕まえろ!!
Our materials are escaping!
Catch them!
There's also a gorilla!
What's going on?!
ｺﾞﾘﾗもいるぞ どういうことだ!?
ﾁｯ 新手か｡
Bah, more of them.
Gintoki, you go on ahead!
銀時 お前は先に行け｡
I'll hold them here!
ここは ｵﾚが食い止める！
Don't pull out your tail like
it's completely normal!
当たり前のように
ｼｯﾎﾟをちぎるな！
Bah, I have no choice.
仕方ねえ！
万事屋 ひとつ貸しだぜ｡
Odd Jobs, you owe me one.
Bring it on, scum!
かかってこい ｻﾞｺども
ﾌｫｰｽの力を見せてやる！
I'll show you the power of the Force!
What the hell are you using?!
お前は なんつうもん使ってんだ！
That's got nothing to do with the Force!
ﾌｫｰｽじゃねえだろ それ
ただの汚ねえﾎｰｽだろ それ！
That's just your dirty hose!
なにをしているんだ 早く行け！
What are you doing?! Hurry up!
あとのことは頼んだぞ 万事屋！
We're leaving the rest to you, Odd Jobs!
かぶき町の野良猫たちと｡
Grant the stray cats of Kabukicho!
誇り高き王に！
And their proud king!
(桂/近藤)真の自由を！
True freedom!
[To Be Continued]
[Preview]
Hoichi, you're just like him.
I once picked up another stray
who was just like you.
The next episode...
"Kabukicho Stray Cat Blues."
[Why is the king of Planet Catnip
gathering the balls of strays...?]
["The Kabukicho Stray Cat Arc"
concludes next episode.]
[See you next time.]